<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">PolyGuide</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="search">App map</string>
    <string name="info_name">Useful information</string>
    <string name="timetable">Schedule</string>
    <string name="doc">Certificates</string>
    <string name="foreign_students">For foreign students</string>
    <string name="portal">E-portals</string>
    <string name="associations">Students communities</string>
    <string name="help">Social services</string>
    <string name="settlement">Freshmen accomodation</string>
    <string name="hostel">Dormitories</string>
    <string name="medical">Medical care</string>
    <string name="grant">Scholarships, social assistance</string>
    <string name="army">Military service postponement</string>
    <string name="trip">Public transport reduced fares</string>
    <string name="support">Material support</string>
    <string name="relax">Recreation departments</string>
    <string name="title_settlement">Instructions on the order of settlement of nonresident freshmen in the dormitory of the campus of SPbPU:</string>
    <string name="social_settlement" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
        <br/>1. Settlement of freshmen is carried out in accordance with the lists provided by institutes and college (lists of provision of
rooms are placed on the SPbPU website in the sections of the institutes).<br/><br/>

        2. Documents required for settling in a dormitory and allocation of a residential tenancy agreement: <br/>
        - passport, copy of passport; <br/>
        - 3 photos 3*4; <br/>
        - registration certificate or military ID (for males);<br/>
        - medical insurance; <br/>
        - medical certificate (086 form);; <br/>
        - certificate (063 form) or vaccinations certificate; <br/>
        - Notarized consent of legal representatives: parents, adopters or guardians (for juvenile students) <br/>

        3. Upon arrival at the university student: <br/>
        -Settles in a dormitory assigned to the institute (college). <br/>
        - Appeals to the one-stop-center for registration and settlement of non-resident citizens for further registration, in accordance with the schedule(Block 2, 8, Nepokorennyh Avenue, St.Ptersburg, (812)248-92-09). <br/>
        - Undergoes a medical examination and receives a certificate in the clinic number 76(Block 1, 11, st. Khlopina, St-Petersburg). <br/><br/>

        4. Freshmen who arrived at SPbPU on weekends or during non-working hours may apply to dormitory number 8 for temporary accommodation.(Block 2, 9, st.Khlopina, St-Peterburg, (812)297-43-50). <br/><br/>

        5. For parents or persons accompanying students, there is a possibility to stay in the superior rooms of the Campus provided availability and advanced booking. Booking and accommodation are carried out by the administration of the complex of additional services (28, Grazhdansky Avenue, St-Petersburg, (812)534-13-68, e-mail: hotel@spbstu.ru). <br/>
        ]]>
</string>
    <string name="social_hostel" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
       <br/> More than 10,000 nonresident and foreign students live in the dormitories of the SPbPU campus.
       All the dormitories are located within walking distance from bus stops or subway stations.<br/><br/>

       The campus is divided into 3 dormitory complexes: <br/>
       - «On Lesnoy Avenue»; <br/>
       - «At Ploschad Muzhestva»;<br/>
       - «On Grazhdansky Avenue».<br/><br/>

       Students in dormitories of SPbPU live in 2, 3 or 4 people in a room.
       All dormitories are equipped with access control systems and external and internal video surveillance systems.
       Entrance to the dormitories is by pass <br/><br/>
       Foreign students of the university normally live in dormitories No. 13 and No. 15 of the complex “on Grazhdansky Avenue” and in dormitories No. 8 and No. 12 of the complex “At Ploschad Muzhestva”;<br/><br/>

 	For a comfortable,  interesting and full life of students there are sport halls, studying roms, self-service laundry, high-speed Internet access and
digital television in the dormitories. They also provide free Wi-Fi Internet zones. On the campus territory, there are sports fields, sports clubs, and a student club. Mini-football, volleyball, basketball, table tennis, chess, and other sports events are held annually, in which participate up to 20 teams from the dormitories.<br/><br/>

       During the entrance examinations and the competition, A dormitory is provided (without accompanying persons) by the direction of the admissions office for nonresident applicants who submitted documents to SPbPU for the summer period of the Admissions Campaign. Information on the settlement of applicants can be obtained by phone +7(812)248-92-09, tmstepanova@spbstu.ru. <br/><br/>

      For accommodation in the dormitory applicants need to:<br/>

      - obtain referral from the admission office; <br/>
      - have an identity document; <br/>
      - have medical certificate (086 form)( with mandatory mark on fluorography examination or a separate certificate on fluorography examination);<br/>
      - applicants under the age of 18 and arriving unaccompanied by parents or other legal representatives for a period of more than three days must have the notarized consent of the parents (one of the parents) or other legal representatives for actions related to the settlement and registration. The document must indicate the type of action for which consent is given: «Я, (Ф.И.О.), даю разрешение на регистрацию по месту пребывания и проживания моего несовершеннолетнего сына(дочери) (паспортные данные и данные свидетельства о рождении) в общежитии ФГАО ВО «Санкт – Петербургский политехнический университет Петра Великого» на период прохождения вступительных испытаний или на период обучения в вышеуказанном университете».<br/><br/>

       Applicants who have arrived at SPbPU during off-hours can contact dormitory number 8 for temporary accommodation (block 2, 9, Khlopin Street, Ploshchad Muzhestva metro station, +7(812)297-43-50).<br/><br/>

       For business partners of SPbPU, as well as for parents of students and applicants, it is possible to stay in the superior rooms of the campus. For booking and accommodation please contact the administration of the complex of additional services at 29, Grazhdansky Avenue 7(812)534-13-68, hotel@spbstu.ru. <br/><br/>

 	Enrolled nonresident full-time students on the basis of Article 39 of Chapter 4 of the Federal Law “On Education in the Russian Federation” No. 273-FL of December 29, 2012 are provided with places to stay in dormitories provided that there are available rooms. <br/><br/>

       For further information please contact:+7(812)248-92-09, uprstg@spbstu.ru.<br/>
 ]]>
 </string>
    <string name="social_relax" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> Polytechnic University is not only educational and scientific, but also a large social complex.
    At all stages of the development of the institute, the maintenance and living of polytechnics was an essential part of its leadership`s performance. A large role in this work has always been played by public organizations of the institute. Currently, the University has recreation facilities on the Karelian Isthmus and on the Black Sea.<br/><br/>

    <u>NORTH CAMP</u><br/><br/>
    The North Camp, founded 50 years ago as a recreation center for the summer training camp of the leading athletes of the Polytechnic University, is currently a favorite vacation spot for its staff and students. Over the years, the camp has changed its location twice, but since 1957 it has been located on the high bank of the Vuoksa River on the southwestern outskirts of the village of Gory (Priozersky District). <br/><br/>

    The formation of the camp and its transformation into a favorite recreation center was possible due to the efforts of leaders and professors of the sports department of the institute, its administration (B.Beltikhin, vice-rector for administrative and economic work, was the main “driving force” of the camp’s construction), trade union organizations, and students.
    One can learn better about the role of the North Camp in the life of polytechnic students through poems, songs and prose, dedicated to it. Their authors are not professional writers, but the overall view of the camp, its nature, helped in saving its unique atmosphere in the poetic word. A professional writer, a member of the Writers' Union of Russia, a graduate of the FRE (faculty of radio electronics) and a researcher at the department of semiconductor physics, Alexander Zhitinsky, is also connected to the North Camp. The wrote there a story, that was first read by him right in the camp.<br/><br/>

    <u>SOUTH CAMP</u><br/><br/>
    In 1959, the newly liberated frontier post in Novomikhailovsky  settlement near Tuapse,  that is located on the shore of a beautiful bay,  was given to the Polytechnic University. Athletes of the university began to organize sports campings here, which later turned into the famous South Camp. Annually more than 500 students and professors of the Polytechnic University come there.<br/><br/>

    Responsible for the distribution of vouchers to the camps:<br/><br/>

     trade union committee of employees<br/>
     +7(812)247-2143<br/>
     195251, 339 room, 1 block, 29, Polyteknicheskaya str., St-Petersburg.<br/><br/>

     trade union committee of students<br/>
     +7 (812) 552-98-53<br/>
     195251, 349 room, 1 block, 29, Polyteknicheskaya str., St-Petersburg.<br/>
     ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="social_medical" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/><u>Clinic №76</u><br/><br/>

    The clinic provides medical care to students, graduate students and residents of higher educational institutions in Kalinin, Vyborg, Krasnogvardeisky, Petrogradsky, Vasileostrovsky districts; students of secondary special educational institutions of the Kalininsky district.<br/><br/>

     Services provided:<br/>
    - Premedical care : medical business, phytotherapy, medical massage, radiology, therapy, dentistry, physiotherapy, functional diagnostics, organization of nursing care, nursing in pediatrics.<br/>
    - Outpatient care, including in day care: obstetrics and gynecology, otolaryngology, ophthalmology, professional aptitude examination, radiology, therapy, functional diagnostics, physiotherapy, surgery, endocrinology, dentistry, therapeutic dentistry, ultrasound diagnostics, urology, health organization, pediatrics, according to the standards and protocols.<br/>
    - Other services: examination of temporary incapacity for work, preliminary and periodic medical examinations, epidemiology. The clinic has a youth counseling, a  a psychologist is available..<br/>
    - One can also get free vaccination against diphtheria, tetanus, measles, rubella, mumps, hepatitis B.<br/><br/>

    Contacts:<br/>
    8(812)534-47-75<br/>
    Block 1, 11, Khlopina str.<br/>
    www.p76om.ru<br/><br/>

    <u> Center for Reproductive Health</u><br/><br/>

    The target group of the Center is students aged 15-24. Directions of assistance provided by the CHI: advisory, informational, diagnostic, therapeutic, preventive, rehabilitative.<br/><br/>

    Center functions:<br/>

    - Diagnostic and medical assistance of doctors: gynecologist, urologist, endocrinologist, dermatologist, dentist, pediatrician, therapist.<br/>
    - Psychological counseling.<br/>
    - Day gynecological hospital.<br/>
    - Group psychological training.<br/>
    - Training of volunteer students for further work in the student environment.<br/><br/>

    Contacts:<br/>
    8(812)534-31-50<br/>
    Block 2, 8, Nepokorennykh avenue. <br/><br/>

    <u> Psychological Service</u><br/><br/>

    The main goal of the Psychological Service is to create conditions for the personal growth of each person who came to us. Throughout the year, volunteers and psychologists conduct weekly various training aimed at self-realization and the disclosure of their personal potential, development of skills that are necessary for any area  (how to behave in a conflict, how to speak on the public, how to introduce yourself so that you are noticed, etc.).  We are also open to any suggestions and ready to conduct that training that interest you.<br/><br/>

    In addition to training, there is a free individual psychologist reception service for students and SPbPU staff.<br/><br/>

    Individual appointments:<br/>
    +7(911)275-85-83 – Olga Vasilenko (camps psychologist)<br/><br/>

    Contacts:<br/>
    studclub.stu@gmail.com<br/>
    8(812)295-27-20<br/>
    Block 2a, 11 Pargolovskaya str.
    <br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="social_grant" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> In accordance with Article 36. “Scholarships and other cash payments” of the Federal Law of December 29, 2012 No. 273-FL “The education act of the Russian Federation””, a scholarship is a cash payment assigned to students in order to stimulate and (or) support them in studying process of the curriculum.<br/><br/>

    Types of scholarships: <br/>
    - state academic scholarship for students;<br/>
    - state social scholarship for students;<br/>
    - state scholarships for graduate students, residents, assistant trainees;<br/>
    - scholarships of the President of the Russian Federation and scholarships of the Government of the Russian Federation;<br/>
    - personal scholarships;<br/>
    - students scholarships  appointed by legal entities or individuals, including those who sent them for studying;<br/>
    - scholarships for students of preparatory departments in cases stipulated by this Federal Law.<br/><br/>

    The sizes of state scholarships are established in accordance with the orders of the university.<br/><br/>

    <u> State academic scholarship for students </u><br/><br/>

    The size of the basic state academic scholarship is 2,200 rubles (for college students - 800 rubles). This scholarship is awarded on the basis of the results of the examinations in the end of the term to students who have “good” or “excellent” marks. At the same time, from the beginning of the first school year to the first intermediate certification, the basic scholarship is paid to all freshmen. <br/><br/>

    Students who have only excellent marks are assigned a state academic scholarship for an excellent student which is 4,400 rubles (1,600 rubles for college students). Students who have been having only excellent marks for the last three terms can apply for a state academic scholarship appointed by a decision of the University Academic Council (100 such scholarships have been established), which is 6,600 rubles (2,400 rubles for college students). <br/><br/>

    Special scholarships for 1st year college students in the amount of 2,000 rubles are assigned before passing the first intermediate certification instead of the basic state academic scholarship for 1st year students enrolled in secondary vocational education programs full-time budgetary form of education, who entered the University on the basis of an excellent certificate of basic general education (average mark of the certificate - 5.0). <br/><br/>

    <u> Merit state academic scholarship for achievements in educational, research, public, cultural, creative and sports activities. </u><br/><br/>

    This scholarship is assigned to students enrolled in educational programs of higher education with special achievements in educational, research, public, cultural, creative or sports activities and is paid in the amount of 10,000 rubles in addition to other types of scholarships awarded.<br/><br/>

    <u>State social scholarship</u><br/><br/>

    In accordance with Part 5 of Article 36 of the Federal Law of December 29, 2012 No. 273-FL “The education act of the Russian Federation”, the state social scholarship is appointed to: <br/>
    - students who are: orphans or children left without parental care,  people who have lost both parents or a single parent during the studying period, disabled children, disabled people of groups I and II, people disabled since childhood,<br/>
    - students exposed to radiation as a result of the catastrophe at the Chernobyl nuclear power plant and other radiation disasters as a result of nuclear testing at the Semipalatinsk testing ground,<br/>
    - students who are disabled as a result of military injury or disease, received during military service, and combat veterans,<br/>
    - students from among citizens who have been serving under contract for at least three years in the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation, in the internal troops of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of the Russian Federation and federal state bodies, in the troops of the National Guard of the Russian Federation, in engineering, road-building military units at federal executive bodies and in rescue military units of the federal executive body authorized to perform tasks in civil defense, foreign intelligence service of the Russian Federation, federal security service agencies, state security agencies and the federal body for mobilization training of state authorities of the Russian Federation in military posts subject to replacement by soldiers, sailors, sergeants, foremen, and dismissed from military service on the grounds provided by subparagraphs "b" - "g" of paragraph 1, subparagraph "a" of paragraph 2 and subparagraphs "a" - "c" of paragraph 3 of Article 51 of the Federal Law of March 28, 1998 N 53-FL "the Conscription and Military Service Act", <br/><br/>

    State social scholarship is also assigned to students who have received state social assistance.<br/><br/>

    The size of the state social scholarship is equal to one and a half times the size of the basic scholarship and amounts to 3,300 rubles (1,200 rubles for college students). <br/><br/>

    State social scholarship is assigned to students on the basis of an application and a certificate issued by the social welfare body at the place of residence (permanent registration) confirming the purpose of state social assistance or another document confirming that they belong to one of the categories of citizens specified in paragraph 5 of Article 36 of the Law on education.<br/><br/>

    Students who receive a state social scholarship are entitled to receive state academic scholarships on a general basis.<br/><br/>

    First and second-year undergraduate students who have excellent or good grades and who belong to the categories of persons entitled to receive state social scholarships are assigned an increased state social scholarship.
    (which is currently amounts to 10000 rubles).<br/><br/>

    <u>Personal and special scholarships</u><br/><br/>

    Scholarships of the President of the Russian Federation and special scholarships of the Government of the Russian Federation are appointed to students who have achieved outstanding success in educational and scientific activities, in accordance with the regulations approved by the President of the Russian Federation and the Government of the Russian Federation.<br/><br/>

    Scholarships appointed by state authorities, local governments, legal entities and individuals, for example, a scholarship of the Government of St. Petersburg, a scholarship of the Potanin Foundation, a scholarship of the Academic Council of SPbPU, are appointed in accordance with their Regulations.<br/><br/>

    Students can apply for various scholarships established by state authorities, local governments, legal entities and individuals, including scholarships of the President of the Russian Federation and special scholarships of the Government of the Russian Federation, personal scholarships of the government of Saint-Petersburg, scholarships of the Vladimir Potanin Foundation, scholarships of KAMAZ OJSC, VTB bank, Alfa-Bank and others. The procedure for the appointment and payment of scholarships
for students, as well as the number and size of these scholarships is determined by the founders of these scholarships.<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="social_army" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
<br/> The postponement of the recruitment into the military for citizens who receive secondary vocational education and higher education is granted by the recruitment committee of the municipality on the basis of subparagraph 2 of article 24 of the Federal Law “On Military Duty and Military Service”.br/><br/>

Important to indicate:<br/>

а) the right to postpone military recruitment is given to full-time students;<br/>
б) full-time student’s study is not a deferment of military service;<br/>
в) The postponement is granted by the military  recruitment committee  of the municipality on the basis of the certificate of the application form No. 2, confirming the citizen’s studies at the university;<br/>
г) postponement to the citizen (student) is given only once (explanation further in the text).<br/><br/>

For reference: deferment from military service is a temporary release of a citizen from the recruitment into the military.
Consideration of the question of the conscription of a citizen for military service shall be adopted by the recruitment committee until the reasons for deferment disappear.  <br/><br/>

The postponement of military service on the grounds of subparagraph "a" of paragraph 2 of Article 24 of the Federal Law "On Military Duty and Military Service" terminates from the moment of disappearance of its grounds.<br/><br/>

Deferral is granted only to citizens "to be called up for military service.”<br/><br/>

The State Duma, by Federal Law No. 185 of July 2, 2013, amended subparagraph “a” of paragraph 2 of Article 24 of the Federal Law “On conscription and military service”, outlined it in a new wording, and legally established the procedure for reading paragraphs of subparagraph “a”.br/><br/>

The law specified in subsection “a” of clause 2 of Article 24 - “the first paragraph”. <br/><br/>

On the basis of sub-clause “a” of clause 2 of Article 24 “On military duty and military service”, a deferment is granted to citizens only once.<br/><br/>

The Federal Law “The education act of Russian Federation” defines education as a purposeful process of education and training in the interests of a person, society, state, accompanied by a statement of the achievement of educational levels set by the state. <br/><br/>

For the record:<br/><br/>

The educational content of the established level and thrust is determined by the educational program. <br/><br/>

The Federal Law “The education act of Russian Federation” establishes the following vocational education levels (clause 5 of Article 10): br/>

- secondary vocational education;<br/>
- undergraduate education (bachelor);<br/>
- undergraduate education (specialty);<br/>
- master;<br/>
- training of highly qualified specialists.<br/><br/>

The right to deferment for military service in connection with education is established by subparagraphs "a" and "b" of paragraph 2 of Article 24 of the Federal Law "On Military Duty and Military Service" <br/><br/>

Specifically, a citizen-student, enrolled in full-time education in educational institutions having state accreditation in the relevant fields of studying, has the right to deferment for military service if he: <br/>

1. Is receiving secondary education (that is, 11 classes) - for the duration of study. <br/>
2. Is getting secondary vocational education in college (technical school); - not received before entering the college (technical school) secondary education (9 classes). <br/>
3. Received before entering the educational organization (college, technical school) basic secondary education, are supposed to graduate from the technical school, college - in the year of attaining 18 years of age (military recruitment age). <br/>
4. is undergraduate and does not have a bachelor’s degree, specialist degree or master’s degree — during the duration of these educational programs, but no longer than the deadlines for higher education under bachelor’s programs established by federal state educational standards. <br/>
5. Is getting a higher education in a specialty program and does not have a bachelor's degree, a specialist degree or a master's degree - during the period of mastering these educational programs, but not more than the established by the federal state educational standards deadlines. <br/>
6. he receives a higher education in a master’s program, and does not have a specialist degree or a master’s degree and has enrolled in a master’s degree program in the year of his undergraduate education in undergraduate programs — during the period of mastering these educational programs, but not more than established by the federal state educational standards deadlines for higher education in graduate programs.<br/><br/>

As mentioned above: the provided deferment from the military recruiting is granted to a citizen only once, except in one of the cases:<br/>

- The first postponement of military recruiting was granted to a citizen in accordance with paragraph 2 (students of secondary general education programs, during the period of mastering these programs, but not longer than the periods of general secondary education established by federal
state educational standards). A citizen has the right to receive another deferment from military service in accordance with paragraph 5 (enrolled in federal educational state educational institutions of higher education, the list of which is established in accordance with paragraph 8 of article 71 of the Federal Law of December 21, 2012 No. 273-FL " The education act of Russian Federation ”- for the period of study at the preparatory departments of these educational organizations at the expense of the federal budget allocations, but not more than one year, and in case of accepting these students to the preparatory departments of these educational organizations in the year of graduating from secondary school);<br/>

-the first postponement of military service call was granted in accordance with paragraph 2 and paragraph 5 of subparagraph “a”; a citizen may re-use the right to postpone being recruited for military services in accordance with paragraph 7 (undergraduates, if they do not have a bachelor’s degree, specialist’s degree or master’s degree, during the mastering of the specified educational programs, but not more than those established by the federal state educational standards educational standards for education undergraduate programs).
The State Duma, by Federal Law No. 185 of July 2, 2013, amended subparagraph “a” of paragraph 2 of Article 24 of the Federal Law “On conscription and military service”, outlined it in a new wording, and legally established the procedure for reading paragraphs of subparagraph “a”. The law specified in subsection “a” of clause 2 of Article 24 - “the first paragraph”. <br/>

- The first postponement of military service was granted in accordance with paragraph 5 (citizens studying at the Federal State High Education Institutes, the list of which is established in accordance with paragraph 8 of Article 71 of the Federal Law of December 29, 2012 No. 273-Federal Law “The education act the Russian Federation "for the period of study at the preparatory departments of these institutes at the expense of the budget allocations of the Federal budget, but not more than one year who study at the preparatory departments of these institutes in the year of secondary school graduation”), or paragraph 8 (citizens enrolled in specialty programs and do not have a bachelor’s degree, specialist’s diploma or master’s degree, during the mastering of these educational programs, but not more than established by federal state standards, educational standards for the period of obtaining higher education programs of specialty.<br/>
- The first postponement of military service was granted to a citizen in accordance with paragraph 7 (a citizen who studies under a bachelor’s program if he does not have a bachelor’s degree, specialist’s degree, or master’s degree) - during the period of mastering these educational programs, but not above established by federal state educational standards , educational standards for terms of higher education in undergraduate programs) citizens can re-use the right to postpone the call for military service in accordance with paragraph 9 (students of “graduate programs, if these students do not have a specialist degree or master’s degree and enrolled in graduate programs in the year of finishing undergraduate program, during the period of mastering these educational programs, but not more than established by the federal state standards, the deadlines for obtaining higher education in graduate programs. <br/><br/>

A citizen enrolled in a Master's program, having a specialist diploma, is not granted deferment from military service.<br/><br/>

Отсрочка предоставляется гражданам, обучающихся на очной форме обучения, на основании подпункта «б» пункта 2 статьи 24 закона, в образовательных организациях и научных организациях по имеющим
государственную аккредитацию программам подготовки научно- педагогических кадров в аспирантуре,программам ординатуры или программам ассистентуры-стажеровки,-в период освоения указанных образовательных программ, но не свыше установленных федеральными государственными стандартами, сроков получения высшего образования - подготовка кадров высшей квалификации, и на время защиты квалификации ученной работы (диссертации), но не более одного года после завершения обучения по соответствующей образовательной программе высшего образования.<br/><br/>

The postponement is granted to citizens enrolled in full-time education, on the basis of subparagraph “b” of paragraph 2 of Article 24 of the law, in educational organizations and scientific organizations for state-accredited training programs for scientific and pedagogical personnel in postgraduate study, residency programs or internship programs, during the period of mastering these educational programs, but not exceeding the established by federal state standards, the time frame for obtaining higher education is the training of higher education personnel qualifications, and at the time of defending the qualifications of academic work (dissertation), but not more than one year after completion of training in the relevant educational program of higher education.<br/><br/>

Attention should be drown!<br/><br/>

Citizens of full-time secondary vocational education or higher education in educational programs aimed at training  religious personnel of religious organizations in the spiritual educational organizations that have a license to carry out educational activities - during the period of study, but over the deadlines for obtaining the relevant education.<br/><br/>

Right to delay the military service.<br/><br/>

On the basis of Article 163 of the Federal Law, amending certain legislative acts of the Russian Federation and recognizing the invalid laws of the Russian Federation in connection with the adoption of the law “The education act of Russian Federation” on the issue of conscription for citizens in internship. “B1” to the Federal Law “On Military Duty and Military Service” (Federal Law of July 2, 2013 No. 185-FL) “citizens enrolled in basic professional educational programs of postgraduate medical education and pharmaceutical education in internship are entitled to defer conscription, provided on the basis and in the manner established by the Federal Law of March 28, 1998 No. 53 "On Military Duty and Military Service for Citizens in Full-time Education in educational institutions that provide state-accredited programs. " Decree of the Government of the Russian Federation of November 18, 2013 “On State Accreditation of Educational Activities”. br/><br/>

In accordance with Part 28 of Article 22 of the Federal Law “The education act of the Russian Federation”, the Government of the Russian Federation decides: <br/>

5. “Establish that the main professional educational programs of higher education (training programs for scientific and pedagogical personnel in postgraduate studies (adjunct), residency programs, assistant training programs) for which the certificate expires on September 1, 2013, but no later than terms of training highly qualified personnel according to the federal state educational standards of higher education  are considered state-accredited until 31 December 2015 "(as amended by Decree of the RF Government of 12.26.2014 number 1537). <br/><br/>

Information provided by the Department of training and recruitment of citizens for military service of the military commissariat of the city of St. Petersburg. <br/><br/>


Detailed information on granting a deferment to military service, as well as on the issue and removal from military registration, full-time students can get in the Military Accounting and Booking Division of the Office of Mobilization Training of SPbPU. <br/><br/>

Department of Military Accounting and the Office of Mobilization Training SPbPU <br/>
+7(812)552-97-43<br/>
Room 143, block 1, 29, Polytekhnicheskaya str. <br/>
]]>
</string>
    <string name="title_trip"> Get public transport discounts. </string>
    <string name="social_trip" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
<br/> Full information on the purchase of tickets and fares for students is available on the official website of the Petersburg Metropolitan State Unitary Enterprise: http://www.metro.spb.ru/ticket.html<br/><br/>

<u> For freshmen who do not have or have lost student contactless smart-card:</u><br/><br/>

All students wishing to use the preferential fare should change to the permanent contactless smart-cards with photos until December 1. You can order a card and pay for making a card (250 rubles):<br/><br/>

- at the box office of metro stations; production time is 10 days, issue in the box office where the application was submitted (when submitting the application, a photograph on paper in the size of 3 * 4 cm is needed ); <br/>
- on the website www.map-line.org; Production time is 10 days, issue at the station’s box office specified in the application or the personalization department (an electronic photograph is required when submitting the application); <br/>
- in the department of personalization at the address: 3, Chernoretsky side str.( “Ploschad Alexandra Nevskogo” metro station), Card production time is on the same day (photograph is not required).<br/><br/>

<u> First-year students (master) and everyone who changed passports:<u> <br/><br/>

Due to the fact that the contactless smart-card was issued on an old passport, it is necessary to issue it on the new passport. To do this, before you go to pay for the card, you need to call the passenger department by phone 350-11-29 or .610-06-94, working hours daily from 08.00 to 19.30.<br/><br/>

<u> On issues of free travel tickets for students from among citizens who have a benefit in the category "Children receiving a pension for the loss of a breadwinner" </u><br/><br/>

Students who already have a free transport card (FTC) in their hands before September 15 should contact the training department (room 333 I of the academic building) to verify and supplement the information for renewing the FTC. <br/><br/>

The initial issuance of a FTC and its extension after September 15 takes place individually at the office of the Transport Organizer, St. Petersburg, located at the address: 32A Rubinstein str., opening hours: from 08:00 a.m. to 7:30 p.m. without breaks and days-off.<br/><br/>

The details of issuing free transport cards to students eligible for free travel can be found on the official website of the St. Petersburg "Organizer of Traffic." <br/><br/>

<u> For students entitled to benefits from among orphans and children left without parental care, for travel by public transport </u><br/><br/>

In accordance with clause 6 of the Decree of the Government of the Russian Federation dated 02.09.2017 No. 1066 of the St. Petersburg  Organizer of Transportation, since 01.10.2017, it blocks previously issued to students entitled to benefits free tickets for public transport. <br/><br/>

The University provides reimbursement of expenses students entitled for benefits associated with travel with city and suburban public transport (except for taxis), within the cost of travel.<br/><br/>

Payment of monthly compensation of the fare in urban transport in the amount of 1035 rubles (at the moment) will be paid along with the basic payments and scholarship. <br/><br/>

For a one-time reimbursement of costs associated with the production of a travel card for travel in public transport (contactless smart card) in the amount of 250 rubles, you should contact the trade union committee of students (room 349 of the first academic building) with a statement about the payment of material assistance and receipt (check) of payment for the production of a ticket. <br/><br/>

For reimbursement of fare in suburban transport, you should contact Liliya Philippova (room 305 of the first academic building), you need to bring your original travel documents confirming the cost of travel.<br/><br/>
It is still possible to reimburse travel expenses once a year to the place of residence and back to the place of study upon presentation of travel documents (tickets) DURING THE MONTH following the month of return. In case of a later submission of documents, reimbursement will not be made. For reimbursement of these costs should also contact Liliya Philippovna (room 305 of the first educational building) with the originals of travel documents. An application form for reimbursement of expenses related to travel to the place of residence and back to the place of study is also attached. <br/><br/>

Application forms are available in electronic form on the University website: “For students” - “Social security” - “Support for needy students”. <br/><br/>

More details of this preferential category of students with information on the extension of previously obtained free travel documents for the 2017/2018 academic year can be found on the website of St. Petersburg "Transportation Organizer." <br/><br/>

The procedure for purchasing tickets by students from among orphans and children left without parental care, and those who lost both parents or a single parent during the period of study, is set out in a letter to the Committee on Science and Higher School of the Government of St. Petersburg.br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="support_a"> Students left without parental care </string>
    <string name="support_b">Students who lost one of the parents</string>
    <string name="support_c">Disabled students (having disabled parents) </string>
    <string name="support_d">Combatants</string>
    <string name="support_e"> Students affected by radiation disasters </string>
    <string name="support_f"> Students with a difficult financial situation </string>
    <string name="support_g"> Students in need of support because of poor health or disease </string>
    <string name="support_h"> Students who became victims of emergencies </string>
    <string name="support_i"> Families consisting of students </string>
    <string name="support_j"> Pregnancy of students and giving birth </string>
    <string name="support_k"> Students with the birth (adoption) of a child </string>
    <string name="support_l">Students taking care for a child</string>
    <string name="support_m">Donors</string>
    <string name="support_n"> Students living in a dormitory (orphans and children left without parental care)</string>
    <string name="support_o"> Recreation organization </string>
    <string name="support_p"> Rehabilitation in the pool </string>
    <string name="title_support_a"> STUDENTS WHO ARE ORPHANS AND LEFT WITHOUT PARENTAL CARE </string>
    <string name="text_support_a" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month. <br/><br/>

    <b> Required documents:</b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - Copy of birth certificate; documents confirming the absence of parents: copies of death certificates; copies of court decisions on deprivation of parental rights or a court decision establishing guardianship; removal of a child from parental custody; recognition of parents as missing; declaration of death; recognition as incapable; copies of the court verdict on the conviction of parents; a medical document on parents\' long-term illness that prevents them from performing their duties; a document confirming that the child was abandoned; materials about the search for parents and others. <br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written.<br/><br/>

    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 11000 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 3 months. <br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_b" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> This category includes students who have lost both or one parent. <br/><br/>

    To receive financial assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month. <br/><br/>

    <b> Required documents: <b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - Copy of death certificate; Copy of birth certificate <br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

    <b> Payment amount:</b> upto 30000 rubles<br/><br/>
Financial assistance in this category can be received one-time, within 6 months from the date of loss.<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_c" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> STUDENTS, PARENTS OF WHICH (ONE OR BOTH) ARE DISABLED PEOPLE(GROUP I OR II) <br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

    <b> Required documents:</b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - A copy of the current certificate of disability of the parent; Copy of birth certificate <br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

   <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

   Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 3 months. <br/><br/>

   DISABLED STUDENTS (GROUP I, II OR III), DISABLED SINCE CHILDHOOD<br/><br/>

To receive financial assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month. <br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - Copy of valid disability certificate <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

   <b>Payment amount: </b> up to 11000 rubles<br/><br/>

   Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 3 months. <br/><br/>

   STUDENTS, WHO ARE DISABLED DUE TO MILITARY INJURY OR DISEASE RECEIVED DURING A MILITARY SERVICE AND (OR) MILITARY ACTIONS VETERANS <br/><br/>

   To receive financial assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month. <br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - A copy of the current certificate of disability (the conclusion of the military-medical commission) and (or) a copy of the certificate of the veteran of military actions <br/>
   - Copy of valid disability certificate <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

  <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

  Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 3 months.<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_d" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> This category includes students from among  citizens who have been serving for at least three years under contract in the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation, in the internal troops of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of the Russian Federation, in engineering, road-building military units under federal executive bodies and in the rescue military units of the federal executive body authorized to carry out tasks in the field of civil defense, the Foreign Intelligence Service of Russia of the Russian Federation, federal security service agencies, state security agencies and the federal body providing mobilization training for state authorities of the Russian Federation in military posts subject to replacement by soldiers, sailors, sergeants, sergeant majors and dismissed from military service on the grounds provided for by sub-paragraphs b. “G” of clause 1, subparagraph “a” of clause 2, and subparagraphs “a” - “c” of clause 3 of Article 51 of the Federal Law No. 53-FZ of March 28, 1998 “On Military Duty and Military Service.” <br/> < br />    Для получения материальной помощи необходимо до 25 числа каждого месяца предоставить комплект документов в Профсоюзную организацию студентов и аспирантов.<br/><br/>

    <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - A copy of a military ID or a copy of a certificate issued by a body of social support for the population at the place of permanent registration (who are disabled and veterans of military actions) <br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>



    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 3 months.<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_e" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> This category includes students affected by the accident at the Chernobyl nuclear power plant, nuclear tests at the Semipalatinsk test site and other radiation disasters. <br/><br/>

To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents </b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - A copy of the certificate of the person injured in the accident at the Chernobyl nuclear power plant and other radiation disasters or the original certificate issued by the body of social support for the population at the place of permanent registration (for those who were affected by the Chernobyl nuclear power plant and other radiation disasters) <br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>


    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 3 months.<br/><br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_f" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> STUDENTS FROM MULTI-CHILDREN FAMILIES <br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

    <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - A copy of the current certificate of a multi-children family; copy of birth certificate <br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>


    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 11000 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 6 months.<br/><br/>

   STUDENTS FROM SINGLE-PARENT FAMILIES<br/><br/>

       To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

  <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - A copy of documents confirming having only one parent (death certificate of one of the parents; certificate No. 025 with a record about the father from the mother`s words a court decision recognizing the parent as missing; a court decision depriving one of the parents of parental rights), a copy of the birth certificate<br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

   <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 11000 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 6 months.<br/><br/>

   STUDENTS, BOTH PARENTS OF WHICH ARE PENSIONERS <br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - Copies of parents\' pension certificates; copy of birth certificate <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>


   <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

   Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 6 months.<br/><br/>

   Students, who are temporarily in a difficult financial situation with regard to travel expenses to the place of residence and back to the place of study on the territory of the Russian Federation, in cases of severe illness or death of parents or close relatives as well as in other emergencies (PARTIAL REIMBURSEMENT) <br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

  <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - Copies of certificates from a medical institution or death certificate and original travel tickets to the place of permanent residence and back to the place of study, a copy of documents confirming the relationship <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

   <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

Financial assistance in this category can be received once.<br/><br/>

   STUDENTS WHO ARE CURRENTLY ARE IN DIFFICULT FINANCIAL SITUATION IN CONNECTION WITH THE DEATH OF CLOSE RELATIVES (EXCLUDING PARENTS DEATH) <br/><br/>

This category includes students who temporarily find themselves in a difficult financial situation due to a serious illness or the death of close relatives (with the exception of the death of parents).<br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - Copy of death certificate; copies of documents confirming the relationship <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 15000 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received once.<br/><br/>

    STUDENTS WHO ARE FROM FAMILIES, WHERE AVERAGE PER CAPITA INCOME IS BELOW THE SUBSISTENCE LEVEL <br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - Copy of certificate of state social assistance (valid for 1 year from the date of state social assistance) <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

   <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 15000 rubles<br/><br/>

Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 3 months.<br/><br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_g" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> STUDENTS, WITH SERIOUS ILL HEALTH , HAVING GOT EXPENSIVE CARE <br/><br/>

    This category includes students with a serious ill health, who have undergone expensive care (including partial payment for medical operations, rehabilitation courses, purchase of expensive medicines, paid medical examinations and examinations, preventive vaccinations against infectious diseases).<br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

    <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - Copies of certificates from a medical institution (including a doctor’s referral from a public medical institution) and personal payment receipts (if the payer is not an applicant, then documents confirming the relationship with the payer) <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>


    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 15000 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received once.<br/><br/>

   STUDENTS WHO ARE AT THE DISPENSARY ACCOUNT IN CONNECTION WITH CHRONIC DISEASES <br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

  <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - Original valid certificate from medical institution <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once in 6 months.<br/><br/>

   STUDENTS,WHO HAVE CLOSE RELATIVES WITH SERIOUS ILL HEALTH, HAVING GOT EXPENSIVE CARE <br/><br/>

   To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - Copies of certificates from a medical institution (including a doctor’s referral from a public medical institution) and personal payment receipts (if the payer is not an applicant, then documents confirming the relationship with the payer) <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

   <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

   Financial assistance in this category can be received once.<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_h" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    This category includes students who are victims of emergencies (natural disasters, accidents, armed conflicts, environmental disasters, fires, epidemics, the destruction or flooding of housing, etc.).<br/><br/>

   To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - A copy of the document of the authorized body confirming the damage from an emergency <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

   <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 11000 rubles<br/><br/>

   Financial assistance in this category can be received once.<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_i" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
   <br/>STUDENTS WHO GOT MARRIED<br/><br/>

   This category includes students who recently got married. <br/><br/>

   To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - Copy of marriage certificate and originals of certificates from both spouses from the place of study <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

   <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 15000 rubles<br/><br/>

   Financial assistance in this category can be received one-time, within 6 months from the date of marriage.<br/><br/>

   STUDENTS WHO ARE MARRIED<br/><br/>

   This category includes families in which both spouses are students..<br/><br/>

   To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Documents required:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - Copy of marriage certificate and originals of certificates from both spouses from the place of study <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

   <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once every 6 months. <br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_j" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> This category includes students who have registered with the medical institution for pregnancy, as well as those who are on maternity leave.<br/><br/>

   To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - A copy of a certificate of pregnancy from a medical institution or a certificate of registration in the early stages of pregnancy <br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

Financial assistance in this category can be received one-time.<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_k" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/>   To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - A copy of the birth certificate of the child (Copy of the court decision on adoption)<br/>
   - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
   - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

   <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 30000 rubles<br/><br/>

Financial assistance in this category can be received one-time, within 6 months from the moment of birth (adoption)<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_l" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> STUDENTS, WHO RAISE CHILDREN ALONE (SINGLE MOTHER / FATHER)<br/><br/>

    This category includes students who raise a child alone (single mother / father)<br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

    <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - A copy of the documents confirming the presence of one parent (death certificate of one of the parents; certificate No. 025 with the record about the father from the mother’s words; the court’s decision recognizing the parent as missing; the court’s decision on depriving one of the parents of parental rights);<br/>
  - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
  - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 11000 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once every 3 months.<br/><br/>

    STUDENTS WHO HAVE CHILDREN <br/><br/>

    This category includes students who have a child..<br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - Copy of child`s birth certificate <br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 7500 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once per semester.<br/><br/>

    STUDENTS, WHO HAVE A CHILD WITH A DRASTIC DETERIORATION IN THE HEALTH, HAVING GOT EXPENSIVE CARE <br/><br/>

   This category includes students who have a child with a serious deterioration in health, who has undergone expensive medical (care (including partial payment for medical operations, rehabilitation courses, the purchase of expensive medicines, paid medical examinations and examinations, preventive vaccinations against infectious diseases) <br/><br/>

   To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

    <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - Copy of the child’s birth certificate and a copy of certificates from a medical institution (a doctor’s referral from a public medical institution) and personal payment receipts (if the payer is not the applicant, then documents confirming the relationship with the payer)br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 11000 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received once.<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_m" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

    <b>Required documetns:</b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - Original current donor certificate <br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>


     <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 3000 rubles<br/><br/>

     Financial assistance in this category can be received once.<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_n" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Office of the campus before the 25th of each month (Dormitory No. 14). <br/><br/>

    <b>Required documents:</b><br/>
    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - Certificate of residence in the dormitory, payment receipt, copies of documents confirming the attitude of the student to the specified category <br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>

     <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 10000 rubles<br/><br/>

   Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once every 3 months. <br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_o" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/>STUDENTS, WHO ARE ORPHANS AND REMAINED WITHOUT THE PARENTAL CARE, SETTING OFF FOR RECREATION TO HEALTH-IMPROVING INSTITUTIONS, LOCATED ON THE TERRITORY OF THE RUSSIAN FEDERATION<br/><br/>

    Students who are orphans and left without parental care, persons from among orphans and children left without parental care, who have lost both or their only parent during training, going on holiday to recreational institutions located in the Russian Federation <br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Office of the campus before the 25th of each month (Dormitory No. 14). <br/><br/>

   <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

   - Application for financial assistance <br/>
   - Original tickets, voucher payment receipt, copies of documents confirming the student’s attitude to the specified category <br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>паспорта, где указаны серия, номер, кем и когда выдан, прописка<br/><br/>

    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 10000 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received once <br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="text_support_p" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> STUDENTS IN NEED OF RECREATIONAL SWIMMING SERVICES REGARDING MEDICAL REASONS <br/><br/>

    To receive material assistance, it is necessary to submit a set of documents to the Trade Union Organization of Students and Postgraduates before the 25th day of each month.<br/><br/>

    <b>Required documents:</b><br/>

    - Application for financial assistance <br/>
    - Help from the medical institution with the appointment of swimming as a recovery and payment receipt (for 6 months)<br/>
    - Copy of tax identification number <br/>
    - Copy of the pages of the passport, where the series, number, by whom and when issued and registration are written <br/><br/>паспорта, где указаны серия, номер, кем и когда выдан, прописка<br/><br/>

    <b>Payment amount:</b> up to 10000 rubles<br/><br/>

    Financial assistance in this category can be received no more than once every 6 months <br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="title_doc">Сcertificates for students, graduates and former students who left the university before the end of their studies</string>
    <string name="text_doc" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    <br/> Currently, there are terminals  located in the lobbies of the ground floor  in the 1st educational building and in the Main educational building.<br/><br/>
    Through these terminals, students can independently receive a number of certificates:<br/><br/>

    Certificates for students to submit:<br/>
    - at parent`s workplace;<br/>
    - at the place of residence for non-resident students (for the provision of benefits to pay utilities;<br/>
    - at the place of study on the program of the second higher education, or study in another educational institute.<br/><br/>

    certificates to students for the submission to social protection to the population bodies (for registration of state social scholarships). <br/><br/>

To receive certificates through the terminal, students must log in the system menu by means of their current electronic pass.<br/><br/>

    Dear students - save your time - use the terminals (for obtaining certificates for submission at the place of demand or the social security bodies!<br/><br/>

In case of problems with self-registration and receipt of the above types of certificates through the terminals, students can apply for information in the Student Accounting Sector - room 361, 3rd floor, 1st Educational Building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya St.<br/><br/>

     <u> Student certificates for  military commissariats)</u><br/><br/>

   Certificates for students from among citizens who are subject to military recruitment are issued in the Department of Mobilization Training - room 143, 1st floor, 1st academic building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya st..<br/><br/>

    <u> Student certificates on scholarships </u><br/><br/>

     Certificates are issued in the Department of Accounting for Payroll Payments, Scholarships and Other Payments -  room.251, 2nd floor, 1st academic building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya st.<br/><br/>

 Certificates can be ordered by calling the department at (812) 552-66-51 or by e-mail: ss.dep@buhfin.spbstu.ru indicating the form of the certificate, full name, the period for which the certificate is required, as well as the place of the demand. Issuance of certificates of income, settlement sheets is carried out upon presentation of a passport (notarized power of attorney). <br/><br/>

     <u> Academic records with a list of subjects studied </u><br/><br/>

     Academic records or certificates about the period of study for those who did not pass the final attestation or have unsatisfactory results, as well as for those who have mastered a part of the educational program and (or) expelled from the educational organization - academic records with a list of studied disciplines - are issued in the directorates relevant institutions.<br/><br/>

     <u> Certificates, giving the right to provide guarantees and compensation to employees, combining work with education </u><br/><br/>

     СThese certificates are issued to students in the directorates of the corresponding institutes.<br/><br/>

     <u>Certificates for students to submit:<br/>
    - at parent`s workplace;<br/>
    - at the place of residence for non-resident students (for the provision            of benefits to pay utilities;<br/>
    - at the place of study on the program of the second higher education, or  study in another educational institute.<br/><br/>
;<br/>
     - others.<br/><br/>

    Certificates  can be received by students without a preliminary order upon presentation of a passport from 13:30 to 17:30 (Friday from 13:30 to 16:30, Saturday and Sunday are days off) in the Student Accounting Sector, room 361, 3rd floor, 1st academic building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str.<br/><br/>

     <u> certificates to students for the submission to social protection to the population bodies (for registration of state social scholarships) </u><br/><br/>

     Certificates  can be received by students without a preliminary order upon presentation of a passport from 13:30 to 17:30 (Friday from 13:30 to 16:30, Saturday and Sunday are days off) in the Student Accounting Sector, room 361, 3rd floor, 1st academic building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str.<br/><br/>

     <u> Certificates and extracts from the document on enrollment for registration of nonresident students of the Russian Federation (as well as foreign citizens recognized as compatriots in the prescribed manner) </u><br/><br/>

     For students who register in the dormitory of SPbPU, it is MANDATORY to have a STATEMENT FORM 1 (from the commandant of the dormitory) or an order to settle in the dormitory. This type of certificate is ordered personally by a student in the Student Accounting Sector – room 361, 3rd floor, 1st academic building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str. Сertificates are issued on the next (after filing of the application) business day in room 361. student reception hours from 13:30 to 17:30 (Friday from 13:30 to 16:30, Saturday and Sunday are days off). <br/><br/>

     <u> Certificates to the Russian pension fund that you are a SPbPU student </u><br/><br/>

     Certificates can be received by students on the next (after filing of the application) business day upon presentation of a passport from 13:30 to 17:30 (Friday from 13:30 to 16:30, Saturday and Sunday are days off) in the Student Accounting Sector, room 361, 3rd floor, 1st academic building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str.
    Apply for a certificate to the pension fund:
https://www.spbstu.ru/students/enquiry<br/><br/>

    <u> Certificates to former students who left SPbPU before the end of the term of study, and graduates who graduated from the university (from 01/01/2014 to the present)</u><br/><br/>

    Certificates can be received by students on the next (after filing of the application) business day upon presentation of a passport from 13:30 to 17:30 (Friday from 13:30 to 16:30, Saturday and Sunday are days off) in the Student Accounting Sector, room 361, 3rd floor, 1st academic building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str.
    Apply for a certificate:
https://www.spbstu.ru/students/enquiry<br/><br/>

    <u> Certificates to former students who left SPbPU before the end of the term of study, and graduates who graduated from the university (from 01/01/2014 to the present)</u><br/><br/>

    Certificates to former students are issued in the student archive upon presentation of a passport from 13:30 to 17:30 (Friday from 13:30 to 16:30, Saturday and Sunday are days off) at the adress: room 358, 3rd floor, 1st academic building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str.<br/><br/>

    <u> Certificates to former Saint Petersburg Electrotechnical University students who studied before December 31, 2015 at the St. Petersburg State University of Trade and Economics, and graduates who graduated from the Saint Petersburg Electrotechnical University (until January 01, 2016)</u><br/><br/>

    Certificates to former students and graduates of Saint Petersburg Electrotechnical University are issued at the address room 208, 2nd floor, 14-a, Polyustrovsky pr. Phone: + 7 (812) 540-14-60, archive-3@spbstu.ru <br/><br/>

    <u> Certificates and unclaimed documents to former students who studied at the St. Petersburg Economics and Technology College of Nutrition until 2015 </u><br/><br/>

    Certificates and documents are issued at 67, Prymorsky pr. Phone: +7(812)430-45-43.<br/><br/>

    <u> Certificates and unclaimed documents to former students who studied at the St. Petersburg College of the Refrigeration Industry until 2015 </u><br/><br/>

    Certificates and documents are issued at the following address: Room Г.2.06., Research building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str. Phone: 534-14-10.<br/><br/>

    <u> Certificates to former students who left SPbPU before the end of their studies, and graduates who graduated from an institution of higher education (before December 31, 2013) </u><br/><br/>

    Certificates are issued in the Archives of SPbPU. Phone: +7(812)534-14-10, Room Г.2.06, Research building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str. http://www.spbstu.ru/structure/archive_spbpu/<br/><br/>

    Unclaimed documents of graduates and expelled students (academic records, diplomas of the technical school, etc.). <br/><br/>

    From 1995 to 2013 are issued at: 2nd floor, 14-a, Polyustrovsky pr. Phone: +7(812)540-78-96.<br/><br/>

   Until 1994, issued at: Г.2.06., Research building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str. Phone:534-14-10.<br/><br/>

   Documents of students who applied to but did not enter SPbPU are issued at: room Г.2.06., Research building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str. Phone: +7(812)534-14-10.<br/><br/>

    <u> Certificates to former students who studied at the St. Petersburg Institute of Mechanical Engineering until 2012 </u><br/><br/>

    Certificates are issued at: room Г.2.06., Research building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str. Phone: +7(812)534-14-10.<br/><br/>

    How and where to pick up unclaimed documents of former students of the Institute of Mechanical Engineering clarify beforehand by phone:+7(812)534-14-10, +7(812)540-78-96.<br/><br/>

    <u> Certificates and unclaimed documents to former students of liquidated branches of the St. Petersburg Polytechnic University of Peter the Great</u><br/><br/>

    - Cheboksary, "Cheboksary Institute of Economics and Management".<br/>
    - Cherepovets, “Institute of Management and Information Technologies”. <br/><br/>

    Certificates and unclaimed documents are issued at: room Г.2.06., Research building, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str.<br/><br/>

    Postal address for sending a request: 195251, 29, Polytechnicheskaya str., St-Petersbrug://www.spbstu.ru/structure/archive_spbpu/<br/><br/>

    The working hours of the SPbPU Archive are from Monday to Thursday from 9 a.m. till 5:30 p.m., on Friday from 9 a.m. until 4:30 p.m. Lunch Break from 1 p.m. till 1:30 p.m . <br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="info_for_foreigner" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    Work with foreign students in SPbPU is carried out by the department of work with foreign students, located at:<br/>
    Rooms 202-204, 28, Grazhdansky avenue<br/><br/>
    Department of work with foreign students:<br/>
    - Receives foreign students on all study matters: (expells, carries out the academic leave process, transfers to other faculties, departments and institutes, prepares renewal of registration, issues certificates and extracts from orders to current students, issues archival references.) <br/>
   - forms an individual case of a foreign student, which includes expert opinion on previous education (if it was received in another country), a notarized translation of documents on the previous education into Russian. For the period of study, the original documents on the previous education are stored in the student’s individual files. To obtain an expert opinion, a student must contact the Center for Expertise of Foreign Education Documents.);<br/>
   - assigns a scholarship to foreign students studying for free;<br/>
   - draws up transport card for preferential usage of public transport in St. Petersburg to foreign undergraduate and graduate students.<br/>
   - draws up diploma and its transcripts to students who have completed studying program and have passed the final examination. To obtain a diploma, you must contact the Department of work with foreign students no later than April. <br/>
   - issues duplicates of diplomas and applications; <br/>
   - draws up contracts for all forms of education; <br/>
   - bills for tuition. Foreign students when paying for tuition must strictly observe the terms of payment specified in the contract.<br/><br/>

   To issue a bank card, you must submit copies of the following documents:<br/>
   - passport (photo page));<br/>
   - migration card;<br/>
   - certificate of migration registration;<br/>
   - visa (if there is no visa, then the page of the passport with Russian transcription);<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="title_foreign"> PROCEDURE FOR ENTRANCE OF FOREIGN CITIZENS BY QUOTA)</string>
    <string name="before"> Before arriving at university </string>
    <string name="after"> Upon arrival at the university </string>
    <string name="info_before" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    STEP 1. FILL IN THE APPLICATION <br/>
    Fill in an application on the website http://russia.study. <br/><br/>

    STEP 2. LEGALIZATION AND TRANSFER OF EDUCATION DOCUMENTS <br/>
   Please note that upon arrival at the university, your education documents must be legalized in the country where you studied.<br/><br/>

   For more information visit the website http://edudoc.spbstu.ru/.<br/><br/>

  Passport and foreign educational documents (diploma and application) must be translated into Russian and notarized before arrival at the university. Before submitting documents to the department for working with foreign students, it is necessary to submit documents on foreign education for taking an expert opinion to the Center for Examination of Foreign Documents on Education: http://edudoc.spbstu.ru/<br/><br/>


  STEP 3. CONFIRMATION OF ARRIVAL AT THE UNIVERSITY <br/>
   After having been accepted for education, you must confirm your arrival at the university 2 weeks before the arrival in order to book a place in the dormitory by e-mail or by phone.<br/><br/>

   You will receive the address of the dormitory from SPbPU employee by e-mail after confirming your arrival and specifying the date and time.<br/><br/>

   Contacts:<br/><br/>

Foreign students department:<br/>
Room 204, floor 2, 28, Grazhdansky avenue<br/>
Working hours:10:00–17:00. Break:13:00–14:00<br/>
Contact person: Elena Gracheva<br/>
a216@imop.spbstu.ru<br/>
+7(812)606-62-33<br/><br/><br/>

Preparatory department for foreign citizens:<br/>
Room 217, floor 2, 28, Grazhdansky avenue. <br/>
Working hours:10:00–17:00. Break:13:00–14:00<br/>
Contact person: Irina Martynova <br/>
martynova_iv@spbstu.ru<br/>
+7(812)606-62-32<br/><br/>

You can get medical insurance upon arrival at the university to receive medical care in a student clinic;<br/><br/>
Make sure your bank card has a limit that allows you to pay for a dormitory, etc. (in case of payment by card). <br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="info_after" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    STEP 1. DORMITORY (IF NECESSARY) <br/>
1. Upon arrival check in the dormitory. <br/>
2. Give the security guardian your passport and you will be taken to the rooms.<br/><br/>
Contacts:<br/>

Dormitories complex "on Grazhdansky Avenue": <br/>
room 104, floor 1, 28, Grazhdanksy avenue<br/>
Working hours:10:00–17:00. Break:13:00–14:00<br/>
Contact person: Yulia Rubleva <br/>
rubleva@spbstu.ru<br/>
+7(812)534-03-58<br/><br/>

STEP 2. REGISTRATION OF DOCUMENTS FOR THE ADMISSION <br/>
On the day of arrival or the next day (exception: weekends) you must appear with the original passport to receive the forms of documents required for admission. <br/><br/>

Contacts:<br/>

Foreign students department:<br/>
Room 204, floor 2, 28, Grazhdansky avenue <br/>
Working hours:10:00–17:00. Break:13:00–14:00<br/>
Contact person: Elena Gracheva<br/>
a216@imop.spbstu.ru<br/>
+7(812)606-62-33<br/><br/>

Preparatory department for foreign citizens:<br/>
Room 217, floor 2, 28, Grazhdansky avenue. <br/>
Working hours:10:00–17:00. Break:13:00–14:00<br/>
Contact person: Irina Matynova<br/>
martynova_iv@spbstu.ru<br/>
+7(812)606-62-32<br/><br/>
Do not forget to take the electronic ticket at the beginning of the corridor. (2nd floor)<br/><br/>

STEP 3. PASSPORT AND VISA DEPARTMENT <br/>
In the customs control zone, you need to receive a migration card with a stamp on arrival in the Russian Federation.
You must save the migration card until the next border crossing.<br/><br/>

On the day of arrival or the next day (exception: weekends), you must report to the passport and visa department of the university with the following documents: <br/>

- Original pssport <br/>
- Original migration card with a note «УЧЕБА»<br/><br/>

All foreign citizens arriving in the Russian Federation must submit documents for registration at the
university\'s passport and visa department within 3 days after crossing the border of the Russian Federation. In case of late migration registration, a fine of 5,000 rubles. and deportation from the Russian Federation!<br/><br/>

All foreign nationals must renew a student visa / registration a month before the end of its term. <br/><br/>
Contacts:<br/>

Passport and visa department:<br/>
Rooms 112/113, 1st floor, 28, Grazhdansky avenue<br/>
Working hours:10:00–17:00. Break: 13:00–14:00<br/>
Contact person: Veronika Glazova<br/>
glazova@spbstu.ru<br/>
+7(812)534-32-22<br/><br/>

STEP 4. ADMISSION TO THE SPbPU<br/>

- Take the electronic ticket at the beginning of the corridor (floor 2) <br/>
- Bring an application («ПАМЯТКА») from room 112/113<br/>
- Students are required to annually take out medical insurance and undergo a medical examination upon arrival. <br/>
- Students are required to pay for accommodation in the dormitory at the box office. <br/><br/>

For enrollment,  applicants for bachelor's, master's, postgraduate courses must provide:<br/>

- original passport<br/>
- photocopy of the first page of the passport and visa (if any) on one page <br/>
- signed «ПАМЯТКА» from room 112/113<br/>
- original documents of education and notarized translation of documents and passports into Russian <br/>
- copy of all passport pages (1 copy);<br/>
- the result of the examination of foreign education documents from Center for Expertise of Foreign Education Documents at: room 515, floor 5, 28, Grazhdansky avenue <br/>
- 10 photos 3 * 4 cm <br/>
- examinations results<br/>
- signed application from the institute <br/>
- completed form <br/>
- medical insurance<br/>
- a health certificate with vaccination notes; a document of the medical institution of the candidate’s country of residence confirming the absence of a human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and AIDS<br/><br/>

For enrollment, you must provide for applicants entering pre-university training: <br/>

- original passport<br/>
- copy of all passport pages (2 copies);<<br/>
- signed «ПАМЯТКА» from room 112/113<br/>
- 6 photos 3 * 4 cm <br/>
- completed form <br/>
- medical insurance <br/>
- a health certificate with vaccination notes; a document of the medical institution of the candidate’s country of residence confirming the absence of a human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and AIDS<;<br/><br/>

Foreign citizens applying for graduate programs pass an interdisciplinary exam, for postgraduate programs an entrance exam / interview.<br/><br/>

Admission to the main educational programs (bachelor, master, postgraduate)<br/>
Foreign students department:<br/>
Room 204, floor 2, 28, Grazhdansky avenue <br/>
Working hours:10:00–17:00. Break:13:00–14:00<br/>
Contact person: Elena Gracheva<br/>
a216@imop.spbstu.ru<br/>
+7(812)606-62-33<br/><br/>

Admission to the Russian language / pre-university training programs <br/>
Preparatory department for foreign citizens:<br/>
Room 217, floor 2, 28, Grazhdansky avenue 28<br/>
Working hours: 10:00–17:00. Break:13:00–14:00<br/>
Contact person: Irina Martynova <br/>
martynova_iv@spbstu.ru<br/>
+7(812)606-62-32<br/><br/>
Box office:<br/>
Room 226, 2nd floor, 28, Grazhdansky avenue<br/><br/>
You must complete an application for training within 5 working days. <br/><br/>
If you have successfully managed with all the steps - congratulations, you entered SPbPU!<br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="title_portal"> Electronic information and educational environment </string>
    <string name="info_portal" formatted="false"><![CDATA[
    The electronic information and educational environment of SPbPU (hereinafter referred to as EIEE) includes electronic information resources, electronic telecommunication technologies, relevant technological means and ensuring that students master the educational programs in full, regardless of the location of the students. <br/><br/>

EIEE provides students with access to the curriculum, work programs of disciplines (modules), programs of practice and final certification, to publications of electronic library systems and electronic educational resources specified in the work programs for all educational programs implemented at the university.<br/><br/>

In addition, EIEE SPbPU provides all types of classes, procedures for assessing learning outcomes, the implementation of which is provided with using e-learning, distance learning technologies.<br/><br/>

Participants in the educational process have the opportunity to form an electronic portfolio of students, including the preservation of work, reviews and assessments for these works from any participants in the educational process. Interaction is created between the participants of the educational process, including synchronous and (or) asynchronous interaction, via the Internet. <br/><br/>

The structure of EIEE SPbPU includes the following information systems and educational resources:<br/><br/>
<u> Distributed e-learning system </u><br/>
Network of educational portals of institutes and MOOC courses on various platforms.<br/>
 Detailed information on the courses: http://open.spbstu.ru/sistema-el/<br/>
 Catalogue of MOOC courses: http://open.spbstu.ru/mooc/<br/><br/>
 <u> Open Polytech </u><br/>
The informational and educational project, the purpose of which is the formation of a unified scientific and educational space, combining electronic resources related to scientific and educational activities.<br/>
 http://open.spbstu.ru<br/><br/>

 <u> Personal account and portfolio </u><br/>
The student\'s personal account is a set of services, including general information about the student; curriculum information; study schedule; performance information; information of the contract and payments for students on an extrabudgetary basis; schedule; electronic portfolio, etc.<br/>
  More ifnormation: http://open.spbstu.ru/lk-learner/<br/>
 Personal account of a student:https://lk.spbstu.ru<br/>
 Personal account of the employee:https://staff.spbstu.ru<br/><br/>

 <u> Information Library Complex </u><br/>
The information library complex provides access to all types of information, including access to the resources of electronic library systems. Since 2005, he has been uniting the Fundamental Library, the Center for Information Library Systems and the Center for Digital Reprography.<br/>
 Information Library Complex website: https://library.spbstu.ru/ru/<br/><br/>

 <u>Universirty websites </u><br/>
The official website of SPbPU and the websites of structural units of SPbPU, including basic institutes, high schools, colleges, lyceum, branch, centers of additional education and retraining, Directorate of basic educational programs, information and library complex.<br/>
 www.spbstu.ru<br/><br/>

 <u> Automated learning management systems </ u> <br/>
Access to information is carried out from the Personal Account, using the information terminal.<br/>
 - ACS «Student»<br/>
 - ACS «Applicant»<br/>
 - IS «Schedule»: http://ruz.spbstu.ru<br/>
 - IS « University load »<br/><br/>

 <u>IT-srvices</u><br/>
 - Cистема видеоконференций: http://acs.spbstu.ru/system/login?domain=acs.spbstu.ru&next=%2Fadmin%3Fdomain%3Dacs.spbstu.ru&set-lang=ru<br/>
 - Internet service Antiplagiarism: https://spbstu.antiplagiat.ru<br/>
 - online proctoring service: http://open.spbstu.ru/centr-proktoringa/<br/>
 - unified authentication system and email: http://open.spbstu.ru/usid/<br/>
 More information: https://www.spbstu.ru/employees/it/<br/><br/>

 <u> Official groups and pages </u><br/>
 - VKontakte: https://vk.com/pgpuspb<br/>
 - Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/pgpuspb?_rdr<br/>
 - Twitter: https://twitter.com/pgpuspb<br/>
 - YouTube channels: https://www.youtube.com/user/SPBMEDIACENTRE<br/><br/>
    ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="campus">Map of the campus</string>
    <string name="building">Maps of the buildings</string>
    <string name="info">Useful information</string>
</resources>